Without meditation, you don't understand
what is best for you.
So today is a day when you have to promise
me that you will meditate every night,
every evening, maybe in the morning also.
Whenever it is possible, if you can go
into meditative mood
you are in contact with
this divine power.
Then whatever is good for you,
whatever good for your society,
for your country,
all is done by this divine power.
You don't have to overpower
the divine power.
You don't have to order.
You don't have to ask.
Just if you meditate you are one with
this all-pervading power
which is another great blessings to us.
Unless and until your Sahasrara is open,
all the blessings of the divine power
cannot come to you. Cannot.
Maybe you might get some money,
you might get some jobs,
you might get this and that.
But your own development is only
possible when you meditate and
your Sahasrara is completely open
and open to truth.
Now the truth is that this
divine power is compassion, is love.
This is the truth.
They say God is love, God is truth.
So the equation has to be made that
truth is love and love is truth.
But it's not a truth that as you have for
your own children, you have for your family.
Attached. Attached love is not truth.
If you're attached to somebody, then you
never see the bad points of that person.
If you are angry with somebody, then you can
never see the good points of that person.
But it's a complete detached love.
And that love is extremely powerful.
Because whenever you project that love to
anyone, you'll be surprised,
the problems of that person will be solved.
His personality will improve.
Everything will work out in a very big way
and his life will be changed.
But if you are attached
to anything whatsoever,
that attachment itself causes problems
and doesn't allow Sahaj to grow.
This attachment could be any kind.
For example, you can be
attached to your country,
attached to your society,
attached to your family.
It can be of any kind.
But when Sahasrara is opened,
you learn one thing — is detachment.
It just happens that you get detached.
Though, I mean, you are not running away.
As it is, in Sahaja Yoga we don't believe
in people who run away from society
and go to Himalayas. All that I call
as escapism. That is not the point.
What happens is that you are there.
You see everyone. You watch everyone.
You know everyone.
You are close to everyone.
But, you are a detached person.
It's a state of mind that
you achieve when Sahasrara is opened.
Then in that state, you are
dealing with people,
you are dealing with problems,
you are dealing with situations,
but, you are not involved in it.
There is no involvement, and that
involvement which you had before
can never give a complete insight —
what is happening, what is the truth is
about any situation.
So this detachment helps.
The greatest thing of the detachment
is that you are not affected.
No use saying that, “Oh, you
are not affected, Mother,
so how can you feel for another person?"
"How can you have compassion
for another person?"
Because if you feel for another person,
then only you can solve the problem.
But this feeling that you have is
again a kind of an attachment.
It is not a real feeling,
because it doesn’t help.
The person is crying; you are also crying.
The person is troubled;
you are also in trouble.
And this does not help that person,
nor will it help you.
So to have detached in no way means
you do not feel the another person.
You do feel. You feel the agony of
that person, the trouble of that person,
of the whole society sometimes,
and of the whole country.
But that you are feeling
is so detached that
the all-pervading power takes over.
First, we must have full faith in
the capability of this all-pervading power.
As soon as you are detached, you say,
“You do it." Finished.
Once you say that, “You are going to do it.
It’s you who is going to do it”,
whole thing changes completely, because
you transfer all your responsibilities,
all your problems, to this divine power,
which is so powerful, which is so capable,
which can work out anything.
So, whenever you think that this problem
you are going to solve, you are the one
who is going to do it, then all right. The
divine power says, “All right, try your
luck.” But if you can really put this problem
to the divine power, it will work out.